Lucy Gouvin

(413) 297-3367 • Pittsburgh, PA • gouvin.lucy@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/lucy-gouvin • github.com/lucygouvin

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Project Management and a passion for user-focused software. Known among teams for the ability to see how all the moving pieces come together to create a finished product. Experienced collaborator with colleagues of all backgrounds who can foster positive team morale among remote, hybrid, or in-person teams.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript, CSS, HTML, React, MongoDB, GraphQL, MySQL, Handlebars.is, Node.is, Express.is, iQuery, Bootstrap, Python
- Agile methodology, Waterfall methodology, Jira, Trello, Slack, GSuite, Microsoft Office, Mac, PC

PROJECTS

PartyMaster | github.com/Albyhua/PartyMaster | stark-hamlet-78991-77b45feb1011.herokuapp.com/

- PartyMaster can add events, invite guests, manage contributions, track RSVPs, and share information all in one app.
- Wrote TypeDefs and Resolvers to handle event creation, guest invitation, editing, comments, RSVPs, and contributions, as well as React components to receive and display the results.
- MongoDB, Mongoose, Apollo, GraphQL, React, Express.js, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

CookBookmark | github.com/sjones-njones/Recipe-Book-Group-3-Project-2 | vast-badlands-21401-8850fb886623.herokuapp.com/

- CookBookmark helps users find new recipes, save them to their account, and print them with perfect formatting.
- Created Handlebars templates for search results, recipe pages, and saved recipes. Implemented responsive CSS.
- MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, Express.js, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, MealsDB API

Grapevine | github.com/lucygouvin/grapevine | lucygouvin.github.io/grapevine/

- Grapevine combines safety statistics from several APIs to provide a detailed evaluation of travel destinations.
- Implemented interactive map, passing coordinates to API fetch requests. Rendered results into a user-friendly UI.
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Mapbox API, OpenWeatherMap API, Precisely API, Amadeus API, jQuery, Bulma

EXPERIENCE

Schell Games, Pittsburgh, PA — Senior Producer

SENIOR PRODUCER, SEPT 2021 - PRESENT ADVANCED PRODUCER, MAY 2018 - SEPT 2021 GAME PRODUCER, JUNE 2016 - MAY 2018

- Led teams of 10-50 developers in VR, location-based entertainment, mobile app, and connected toy products.
- Developed tools, templates, tutorials, Jira customizations, and best practices for the Production department.
- Defined requirements, shared creative vision, and managed scope with clients; delivered on time and on budget.
- Reported progress, risks, schedule, and dependencies to clients, external stakeholders, and studio leadership.
- Shipped experiences include: Out of Scale: A Kurzgesagt Adventure, I Expect You To Die DLC/Localization updates, UPMC Odyssey app, Pittsburgh Zoo app, Osmo Monster, and Children's Museum of Houston S.E.C.R.E.T. Spy Game update.

Fay Games, Amherst, MA — *Producer*

MAY 2015 - JUNE 2016

- Anticipated needs of a fast-paced production of educational mobile game by solving problems in advance.
- Facilitated communication with a remote team of 7 through group meetings and individual follow-up.
- Adapted to evolving priorities by assigning tasks, giving notes, and monitoring progress.

Word Snack HD, Hampshire College, Amherst, MA — Art Producer

FALL 2014

- Worked with a team of 40 students to create a mobile word game, directly managing twelve 2D and 3D artists.
- Structured meetings and presentations to efficiently gather and give feedback in a short production timeline.
- Communicated between departments to ensure all art needs were satisfied and deadlines met. Shipped 2014.

Real Live Theater, Hadley, MA — Company Manager, Founding Member

SUMMER 2013 - JUNE 2016

- Updated records, facilitated meetings/rehearsals, distributed information for productions and the company.
- Coordinated a multi-state theatrical tour with venues, actors, director, and local publicity.

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania, Online —Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate

MAY 2023 - NOV 2023

- Excelled in fast-paced, career-focused bootcamp and mastered a variety of front back end technologies.
- Individual projects include a blog site, note taking site, calendar scheduler, weather dashboard, and password generator.

Smith College, Northampton, MA — Double B.A., Studio Arts and Economics, cum laude

SEPT 2012 - JUNE 2016

- Participated in Smith-Tuck Business Bridge Program introduction to business school for liberal arts majors
- Kahn Institute scholar selected to participate in multidisciplinary independent research.